<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source Camp @Iași</title>
    <description>The National Open Source Camp @Iași</description>
    <link>https://oscamp.eu/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://oscamp.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>First steps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, to do great things, you need some inspiration. You need great people to give you that one spark that will make you conceive a great idea and build upon it until it grows beyond measure. And other times, you just need some support. But what happens when you receive both from some awesome founders?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Source Camp isn’t an event without history. Although its concept is a little different from its successor, OSCamp is based upon the idea launched by Sabin Buraga and Andreea Popescu in 2014 called Open Source Iași (OSI). The event was hosted in Iași, Romania, but its target was only the local developer scene, gathering about 100 participants in a 10 hours event that covered, through multiple speakers, Open Source technologies and their impact. The event was the first of its kind in this part of Romania and it had quite the success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you could say Open Source Camp has a history and isn’t just a new event built by some enthusiastic student, but an event that has a good brick to stand on. This year, with the help of the original team, we take our aim to overcome the accomplishments of the previous event, taking our event to a national level and hopefully gathering more than 300 students and developers to a 2 day meetup for tech talks. And to pump it all up, we are offering workshops for multiple skill levels and a hackathon with some awesome goodies for the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for you beautiful people reading this, we really hope you’ll support us in our initiative and through us, the Open Source community of Romania. And of course, we can’t wait for you to join (c’mon, we have cookies, we promise).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://oscamp.eu/blog/first-steps-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://oscamp.eu/blog/first-steps-2016</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Source Camp 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, the step we’ve been waiting for has been taken by a large amount of tech industry giants and important figures. From the beginning of the IT industry, the Open Source trend has been an element of geek legends, but the myth becomes reality in a push of the industry towards greater grounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our enthusiasm, we want to share the beautiful things this old taboo subject has to offer in the software industry, with the help, of course, of great minds with state of the art skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSCamp is an event specially dedicated to all those interested in the open source perspective. It aims to be the biggest event of its kind in Romania. Hosted in Iași, it is challenging over 300 participants to take part in a three day run over tech talks, workshops and an awesome hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSCamp is organized in collaboration and with the full support of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.info.uaic.ro/bin/Main/&quot;&gt;Faculty of Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uaic.ro/&quot;&gt;“Alexandru Ioan Cuza” University&lt;/a&gt;, Iași and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ccsir.org/&quot;&gt;Cyber Security Research Center from Romania (CCSIR)&lt;/a&gt; for the Romanian developer and future developer community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;join-us&quot;&gt;Join us!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to build a conference with a lasting future and huge impact. In that idea, more than 300 faculty and high school students, developers and enthusiasts are expected to join our event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSCamp is the first conference of its kind and magnitude in Romania. Participants of all kind have their place in our event. From the guru developer to the curious student, we fit all perspectives and interests. We aim to distinguish ourselves by a unique atmosphere and a general build-up of great minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between everything, OSCamp is also a great place for companies to find talent based on real world and motivated interest in the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city of Iași is where the OSCamp initiative will be hosted, a city that is becoming known for its IT community and IT related events, offering a full range of services and a good quality infrastructure to help get everything in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we are at our starting point, great efforts are being pushed into building OSCamp as a nation wide event with greatness inside. OSCamp is an awesome opportunity to kick the open source community up a few notches and upgrade its foundation to something even more special, creating the event that this subject deserves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://oscamp.eu/blog/open-source-camp-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://oscamp.eu/blog/open-source-camp-2016</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
