<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source Camp @Iași</title>
    <description>The National Open Source Camp @Iași</description>
    <link>https://oscamp.eu/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://oscamp.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for sponsors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sponsoring &lt;em&gt;Open Source Camp&lt;/em&gt; offers you the opportunity to present your company in a professional and innovative development environment. You’ll have an unique chance to find talent based on real world and motivated interest in the open source community, in order to recruit employees for your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participating to our conference, you will have the possibility to make your products available to all the participants of the event. As well, you will meet some of the greatest speakers and developers in Romania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a sponsor of OSCamp 2016, you will be supporting the work of a significant open source community which will be the foundation of the technological development and innovation in Romania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a list of sponsoring packages at &lt;a href=&quot;https://oscamp.eu/sponsor-brochure/&quot;&gt;oscamp.eu/sponsor-brochure/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you like to sponsor OSCamp? Please send us an email to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#115;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#115;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://oscamp.eu/blog/call-for-sponsors-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://oscamp.eu/blog/call-for-sponsors-2016</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for proposals</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are looking for papers related to any aspect of the open source domain, built for various skill levels, beginner to advanced. &lt;em&gt;Open Source Camp&lt;/em&gt; is a conference that fits all perspectives and interests and we would like to hear about your experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presenting at OSCamp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will accept a variety of presentations, from reports on academic related work and case studies to applications, tutorials (only for workshops) and tools. As long as the presentation is interesting and brings something new to the open source community, it will be considered for inclusion in the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of contributions that you can present:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk on conference:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;15 minutes (6 slots)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;30 minutes (10 slots)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;45 minutes (4 slots)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;These are allocated depending on your preference and scheduling constraints. At the end of the talk there will be a Q&amp;amp;A session.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Workshop&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;These session must follow a topic related to open source technologies and tools and can be variable in their lenght.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to share something of your work? Would you like to share your knowledge? If so, please send us an email to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#112;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#115;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#112;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#115;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://oscamp.eu/blog/call-for-proposals-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://oscamp.eu/blog/call-for-proposals-2016</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for partners</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you want to help build a conference with a lasting future and big impact? We are happy to announce the launch of the &lt;strong&gt;Open Source Camp 2016&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will bring together important organizations and companies and one of the biggest universities in Romania for a two day event in Iași.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to ensure that every student or developer interested in open source will have the opportunity to participate to this event. Use your networks to reach a large number of people and help promote information about the event nationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a partner of OSCamp 2016, you will have the possibility to support the work of a significant open source community and you will have a certain package of benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you like to be a OSCamp partner? Please send us an email to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#117;&quot;&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#099;&amp;#097;&amp;#109;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#101;&amp;#117;&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://oscamp.eu/blog/call-for-partners-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://oscamp.eu/blog/call-for-partners-2016</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First steps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, to do great things, you need some inspiration. You need great people to give you that one spark that will make you conceive a great idea and build upon it until it grows beyond measure. And other times, you just need some support. But what happens when you receive both from some awesome founders?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Open Source @Iași&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Source Camp isn’t an event without history. Although its concept is a little different from its successor, OSCamp is based upon the idea launched by Sabin Buraga and Andreea Popescu in 2014 called &lt;a href=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Open Source Iași (OSI)&lt;/a&gt;. The event was hosted in Iași, Romania, but its target was only the local developer scene, gathering about 100 participants in a 10 hours event that covered, through multiple speakers, Open Source technologies and their impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#####Speakers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reps.mozilla.org/u/popescu_andreea_z/&quot;&gt;Andreea Popescu&lt;/a&gt; (Mozilla Rep) from Iasi, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/in/mflorea&quot;&gt;Marius Dumitru Florea&lt;/a&gt; (XWiki) from Iasi, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/in/flaviusolaru&quot;&gt;Flavius Olaru&lt;/a&gt; (XWiki) from Iasi, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://about.me/stefanbc&quot;&gt;Stefan Cosma&lt;/a&gt; (Koding) from Sibiu, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jakob.cosoroaba.ro/&quot;&gt;Jakob Cosoroaba&lt;/a&gt; (Txt2Teach) from Bucharest, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://purl.org/net/busaco&quot;&gt;Sabin Buraga&lt;/a&gt; (Faculty of Computer Science) from Iasi, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reps.mozilla.org/u/ioana_chiorean/&quot;&gt;Ioana Chiorean&lt;/a&gt; (Mozilla Rep) from Cluj-Napoca, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ciprian Amariei (2wit) from Iasi, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lakatos88&quot;&gt;Alex Lakatos&lt;/a&gt; (Mozilla Rep) from Cluj-Napoca, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blankdots.com/&quot;&gt;Ștefan Negru&lt;/a&gt; (Faculty of Computer Science) from Iasi, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoiasi.ro/bin/Structure/vcosmin&quot;&gt;Cosmin Varlan&lt;/a&gt; (Faculty of Computer Science) from Iasi, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/in/doruilasi&quot;&gt;Doru Ilasi&lt;/a&gt; (Aplix) from Brasov, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://systems.cs.pub.ro/people/razvan.deaconescu/&quot;&gt;Razvan Deaconescu&lt;/a&gt; (ROSEdu &amp;amp; UPB) from Bucharest, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/pub/flavius-anton/36/b92/628&quot;&gt;Flavius Anton&lt;/a&gt; (ROSEdu &amp;amp; UPB) from Bucharest, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alex.eftimie.ro/&quot;&gt;Alex Eftimie&lt;/a&gt; (ROSEdu &amp;amp; UPB) from Bucharest, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matei Oprea (ROSEdu &amp;amp; UPB) from Bucharest, Romania&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#####Schedule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;09:00 Opening&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;09:15 &lt;a href=&quot;http://slid.es/jcsrb/open-source-iasi-2014&quot;&gt;“Cu Open Source îți iei destinul în propriile mâini”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://jakob.cosoroaba.ro/&quot;&gt;Jakob Cosoroabă&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;09:45 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/popescu_andreea/how-to-get-involved-in-mozilla-32258180&quot;&gt;“How to get involved in Mozilla”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://reps.mozilla.org/u/popescu_andreea_z/&quot;&gt;Andreea Popescu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:15 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/busaco/sabin-buraga-date-de-5-stele&quot;&gt;“5-star Open Data”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://purl.org/net/busaco&quot;&gt;Sabin Buraga&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:45 “După 7 ani de WoUSO” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/pub/flavius-anton/36/b92/628&quot;&gt;Flavius Anton &amp;amp; Matei Oprea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11:15 Coffee break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11:30 &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/stefanbc/mozilla-open-source-event-presentation-of-koding&quot;&gt;“Koding”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://about.me/stefanbc&quot;&gt;Ștefan Cosma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12:00 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/blankdots/open-war&quot;&gt;“Open WAR (Web Applications and/for Research)”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://blankdots.com/&quot;&gt;Ștefan Negru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12:30 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/MariusDumitruFlorea/developing-the-xwiki-software-32344899&quot;&gt;“Developing the XWiki software”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/in/mflorea&quot;&gt;Marius Florea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;13:00 Lunch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14:00 “Cum să fii un bun magician în baze de date” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/in/doruilasi&quot;&gt;Doru Ilași&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14:30 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/flaviusolaru/bookmarletapp-presentation-32342463&quot;&gt;“XWiki Bookmarklet”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.linkedin.com/in/flaviusolaru&quot;&gt;Flavius Olaru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15:00 “Arduino: Open Source Imagination” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoiasi.ro/bin/Structure/vcosmin&quot;&gt;Cosmin Vârlan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15:30 &lt;a href=&quot;https://alexlakatos.github.io/slides/open-source-iasi/&quot;&gt;“Developing for Firefox OS”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lakatos88&quot;&gt;Alex Lakatos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;16:00 Coffee break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;16:15 “Women in Open Source” - &lt;a href=&quot;https://reps.mozilla.org/u/ioana_chiorean/&quot;&gt;Ioana Chiorean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;16:45 &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/folderview?id=0By6_as_hLrdoYkRCV0xLLUVBZ2M&amp;amp;usp=sharing&quot;&gt;“ROSEdu: Starea comunității”&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://systems.cs.pub.ro/people/razvan.deaconescu/&quot;&gt;Răzvan Deaconescu&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://alex.eftimie.ro/&quot;&gt;Alex Eftimie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;17:15 “Open Web Dev” - Ciprian Amariei&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;17:45 The end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was the first of its kind in this part of Romania and it had quite the success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you could say Open Source Camp has a history and isn’t just a new event built by some enthusiastic student, but an event that has a good brick to stand on. This year, with the help of the original team, we take our aim to overcome the accomplishments of the previous event, taking our event to a national level and hopefully gathering more than 300 students and developers to a 2 day meetup for tech talks. And to pump it all up, we are offering workshops for multiple skill levels and a hackathon with some awesome goodies for the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for you beautiful people reading this, we really hope you’ll support us in our initiative and through us, the Open Source community of Romania. And of course, we can’t wait for you to join (c’mon, we have cookies, we promise).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://oscamp.eu/blog/first-steps-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://oscamp.eu/blog/first-steps-2016</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Source Camp 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, the step we’ve been waiting for has been taken by a large amount of tech industry giants and important figures. From the beginning of the IT industry, the Open Source trend has been an element of geek legends, but the myth becomes reality in a push of the industry towards greater grounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our enthusiasm, we want to share the beautiful things this old taboo subject has to offer in the software industry, with the help, of course, of great minds with state of the art skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSCamp is an event specially dedicated to all those interested in the open source perspective. It aims to be the biggest event of its kind in Romania. Hosted in Iași, it is challenging over 300 participants to take part in a three day run over tech talks, workshops and an awesome hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSCamp is organized in collaboration and with the full support of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.info.uaic.ro/bin/Main/&quot;&gt;Faculty of Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uaic.ro/&quot;&gt;“Alexandru Ioan Cuza” University&lt;/a&gt;, Iași and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ccsir.org/&quot;&gt;Cyber Security Research Center from Romania (CCSIR)&lt;/a&gt; for the Romanian developer and future developer community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Join us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our aim is to build a conference with a lasting future and huge impact. In that idea, more than 300 faculty and high school students, developers and enthusiasts are expected to join our event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OSCamp is the first conference of its kind and magnitude in Romania. Participants of all kind have their place in our event. From the guru developer to the curious student, we fit all perspectives and interests. We aim to distinguish ourselves by a unique atmosphere and a general build-up of great minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between everything, OSCamp is also a great place for companies to find talent based on real world and motivated interest in the open source community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city of Iași is where the OSCamp initiative will be hosted, a city that is becoming known for its IT community and IT related events, offering a full range of services and a good quality infrastructure to help get everything in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we are at our starting point, great efforts are being pushed into building OSCamp as a nation wide event with greatness inside. OSCamp is an awesome opportunity to kick the open source community up a few notches and upgrade its foundation to something even more special, creating the event that this subject deserves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://oscamp.eu/blog/open-source-camp-2016</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://oscamp.eu/blog/open-source-camp-2016</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
